scentsy.net 2019-10-21

# Scentsy Corporation Privacy Policy Information | Scentsy.com

## Introduction

Scentsy, Inc., a company incorporated under the laws of the State of Idaho, U.S.A., (collectively referred to herein as “Scentsy,” “we,” “us” and “our”) understands the importance of privacy of individuals (referred to as “users” and “you”). Scentsy also maintains websites for several affiliate companies and brands. This privacy notice outlines the personal information Scentsy may collect and how Scentsy will use and disclose that information. Scentsy is committed to protecting your personal information. We have adopted the following policies with regard to collection and distribution of information

## Information Collection

Scentsy may collect two different types of information, Personally Identifiable Information and Non-Personally Identifiable Information. “Personally Identifiable Information” (“PII”) is information that identifies you as an individual – for example, your name, address, telephone number, email address, credit card information, billing address and shipping information. “Non-Personally Identifiable Information” (“Non-PII”) is aggregated information, demographic information, IP addresses, user behavior data from web interaction metrics tools and any other information that does not reveal your specific identity.

Scentsy may also collect PII about you from, among other places: information you provide directly to us, information regarding the services that Scentsy currently provides or has previously provided to you, information Scentsy receives from our affiliated entities or third parties relating to the establishment of our relationship or the provision of services to you.

This information can be received in any manner, including in-person discussions, telephone conversations, and electronic or other written communications.

During the Independent Consultant enrollment process, or while purchasing product on Scentsy maintained websites, Scentsy may collect PII about you that may be considered sensitive. Scentsy will never share your data with third parties other than our agents.

## Cookies

We may collect information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer’s hard drive. They help us to improve our site and to deliver a better and more personalized service. They enable us to estimate our audience size and usage pattern, to store information about your preferences (and so allow us to customize our site according to your individual interests), to speed up your searches and to recognize you when you return to our site. You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our site. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you log on to our site.

## Information Use

Scentsy may collect PII about you to establish or maintain our relationship with you, respond to your inquiries, provide you with services you have requested, keep you informed of services we think may be of interest to you, personalize your experience with us, and other reasons.

Without PII, Scentsy may be unable to provide you with the services you have requested.

## Disclosure of Information

Scentsy does not sell or lease PII about you to others.

Scentsy may share PII about you with others as permitted by contractual agreement or as required by law, such as our affiliates, third parties in connection with the provision of services to you, government entities and regulatory bodies, and those with whom you have requested us to share information.

Unless restricted by law, regulation, contract or professional standards, Scentsy may transfer PII about you outside of the United States to other countries for the purposes described in this privacy notice.

Scentsy will not share PII about you with an unaffiliated third party who is not performing services for us without first obtaining your permission, except if such sharing is otherwise permitted by this privacy notice.

Scentsy will provide PII about you to the following types of third parties for the associated reasons:

  * Carriers: Scentsy will provide your name and address to companies which provide a delivery service between Scentsy and its customers as a means of delivering our products to you as quickly as possible.
  * Financial Institutions: Scentsy will provide financial institutions with your payment information, name, address, and phone number in order to process any orders placed by you and complete payment of the transaction to Scentsy.
  * Logistics: Scentsy will provide your name, address and phone number to those entities or people within our network of distribution in order to process and ship your orders with speed and accuracy.

Scentsy requires third parties who perform services for us to agree to treat PII about you confidentially and securely. Prior to collection of your PII, any such third parties are required to sign a service agreement, which includes the privacy policy outlined here. Note that this statement does not address the privacy practices or polices of our Independent Consultants. However, Scentsy Independent Consultants agree, as specified in our Policies and Procedures, to comply with all applicable privacy laws and regulations.

Notwithstanding any other provision of this notice or the Terms and Conditions of Use to the contrary, we reserve the right to disclose and use your PII if we believe that we are required to do so: (a) by law; (b) in response to legal process, for example, in response to a court order or a subpoena; (c) in response to a law enforcement agency’s request; (d) to enforce our other terms, conditions, or policies; (e) to protect our operations; (f) to protect the rights, privacy, safety or property of Scentsy, you or others; and/or (g) to permit us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages we may sustain. For example, we may to the fullest extent the law allows, disclose PII about you to law enforcement agencies to assist them in identifying individuals who have been or may be engaged in unlawful activities.

Because Non-PII does not personally identify you, we reserve the right to use Non-PII, and to disclose Non-PII to third parties, for any purpose.

## Access

You may request access to the PII that Scentsy has about you. You may also request the correction, amendment or deletion of PII about you that is inaccurate. Scentsy will treat requests for access, correction, amendment or deletion of PII about you in accordance with its internal policies and applicable legal requirements.

## Information security and integrity

Scentsy maintains reasonable physical, administrative and technical safeguards to protect PII from loss, misuse, or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. Our personnel and the personnel of our affiliates are provided access to PII about you only if they have a need to know the information in connection with a legitimate business purpose, such as (a) the provision of services to you or (b) to help identify other services that Scentsy and its affiliates offer that may be of interest or use to you.

Additionally, Scentsy will only use PII for the purpose which it was intentionally collected. Scentsy will take reasonable measures to safeguard your information and ensure that is accurate, complete and current.

## Privacy shield Frameworks

Scentsy, Inc. complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries transferred to the United States pursuant to Privacy Shield. Scentsy, Inc. has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles with respect to such data. If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and data subject rights under the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, Scentsy is subject to the regulatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.

Scentsy takes a self-assessment approach to verify that we are within compliance of this policy. Scentsy employees are trained to adhere with this privacy policy and Scentsy administers discipline to those employees who do not comply.

Pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, EU individuals have the right to obtain our confirmation of whether we maintain personal information relating to you in the United States. Upon request, we will provide you with access to the personal information that we hold about you. You may also correct, amend, or delete the personal information we hold about you. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data transferred to the United States under Privacy Shield, should direct their query to [legal@scentsy.com](mailto:legal@scentsy.com). If requested to remove data, we will respond within a reasonable timeframe.

Scentsy will provide an individual opt-out choice, or opt-in for sensitive data before we use it for a purpose other than which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized. To request to limit the use and disclosure of your personal information, please submit a written request to [legal@scentsy.com](mailto:legal@scentsy.com)

In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Scentsy’s accountability for personal data that it receives in the United States under the Privacy Shield and subsequently transfers to a third party is described in the Privacy Shield Principles. In particular, Scentsy, Inc. remains responsible and liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if third-party agents that it engages to process the personal data on its behalf do so in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, unless SCENTSY proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Scentsy commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information transferred to the United States pursuant to Privacy Shield. European Union individuals with Privacy Shield inquiries or complaints should first contact Scentsy by email at [legal@scentsy.com](mailto:legal@scentsy.com) or via post at:

Scentsy, Home Office.  
2701 E Pine Ave.  
Meridian, ID 83642

Attention: Legal Department

Scentsy has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit <http://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers> for more information and to file a complaint. This service is provided free of charge to you.

If your Privacy Shield complaint cannot be resolved through the above channels, under certain conditions, you may invoke binding arbitration for some residual claims not resolved by other redress mechanisms. See Privacy Shield Annex 1 at <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction>

## Changes to this privacy notice

Scentsy reserves the right to change this privacy notice. Any changes to this notice will become effective upon posting of the revised notice on the Internet or as required by law.

Please note that email communications are not necessarily secure. Accordingly, you should not include credit card information or other sensitive information in your email correspondence to us.
